Twenty-three.
Why would the implication?
It's a faster first Christmas, but it's a brighter future.
Thank you.
Father God, we love you.
God, we come to you grateful for our community.
God, I just pray that as our hometown continues to grow and thrive and possible,
minimum is found, that you'll continue to work through this group and allow us to have
unity as a leadership.
Give wisdom to the board members.
Give wisdom to the community.
We seek what's best for my Emma.
God, we love you.
We pray that we honor you with every decision we make, with every action that's taken.
And we pray that we'll all be more like Jesus because of it.
And as an end, we pray.
Amen.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America.
And to the Republic for which you stand.
One nation, under God, in the visible, with liberty and justice and all.
For both of us, let's give the personal appearances.
Doctract contracts to track.
Let's say something wrong.
Or is it just fine?
Okay.
The track called track.
Police is standard operating.
It's just police.
It doesn't.
Police.
Okay.
Standard operating procedures provide public access.
To policies.
And provide internal.
Oh, really?
At this.
In training.
Not to exceed 5,663 dollars.
So in your packet tonight.
And we're asking both the council and administrative prove this.
Is a one year contract with.
For doc track.
Software.
And what it does.
It's documents just like it sounds.
What we're mainly purchasing it for is for our policies.
We have a lot of statutory required policies.
But just policies in general, especially once we can link to our website.
We can also create standard operating procedures.
There's other things we can track in there that everybody.
All the departments are thinking about different things ways they can use it.
And some of the things that can do.
It reminds you when to review that policy or that document.
It allows again for public access on the website.
It allows for a employee to a test that they have read the policy.
And it also allows the departments create a quiz to make sure they understand what the policy says.
So that's what we're asking not to exceed 5,663.
So what's going to be the policy on this program to govern the policies.
I'm going to ask you a review next week.
That's what I was, Mike, one of the redentant, who says a policy that states how policy is
created and then I thought that's what's going on with the more I read it.
It's a chicken and egg kind of thing, I feel like.
Yeah, it's just, but this is not really replacing that.
This is just a tracking ball or a tracking.
Yeah, it's a software, it's an automated software that we'll do that.
But we do have a, the council in 2015 approved a policy to create, revise and repeal policy.
At the next meeting, your next council meeting I'll ask you to revoke that policy because we're going to create a standard operating procedure.
So policies are more serious.
We kind of had that discussion since 2015 that we really need to have real separation between what the definition of policy is and a standard operating procedure.
So this isn't cost every year.
That, so there won't be the implementation fee of 750, that we the 4,163 for the internal users and then the public portal of 750.
So some of that will be repeating costs.
So by public portal, this also gives us the ability, which we publish from public facing policies.
Then you all will be able to see him.
We have a public, we'll be able to log in and see him.
But it's kind of creates a small library in a cloud-based system.
And you can control the revision that we do internally, doing updates.
Do anybody, anybody in a community can log in?
What are the policies?
On the ones that are public, yes.
So if you don't have the software, what happens?
We could have them, what can do what we're doing now, which isn't working well.
It's internal, it's kind of clunky.
You could still publish them and be a link on the website for each one that we do.
This does create reminders, which is really nice.
It also is going to track lots of other, we have lots of other documents that get passed around and people sign them.
Instead of physically signing them, it'll be electronic passing around.
Is there no one else out there that does this type of software for cheaper?
This is the cheapest I found by far.
And it's very simple.
That was my favorite part about it.
We wanted something simple, just to track documents.
And this does more than what we even, I was even looking for.
But yeah, this was the cheapest by, I think, at least $2,000.
But it was like, it was about 7,500 and they went up like $14,000.
Yeah.
So this is not paid off all the time.
We're just trying to get into the 21st century.
Exactly.
So this is all in documents.
And then wondering who has it, who made what revision, things like that?
Screening any kind of...
ROI on this as far as what time are we wasting going through the current process compared
to what we'll be spending with this.
The anticipation is it's going to be tremendous because this is something we drastically
struggle with.
You know policies any time you're trying to do documentation that's never on the first of
anybody's list of the responsibilities in a job.
And so it's something that you always struggle trying to get into documentation, policies,
things like that, you're always doing it on your spare time.
And so it's, you know, will pass around a policy and say we did our part in this department and
then it goes to another department that sets up somebody's desk or their inbox for a
period of time.
And then by the time it goes around and makes all the rounds, you're starting all over again
because it's something else that's changed.
And so we end up with this laundry list of the changes that we're going to be trying to make
these policies and it gets massively confusing, confusing, and so this is something that
if we even adopt a system like this, now we've got an actual electronic library for
saying that we can check things in and out.
It tracks kind of a workflow of whose responsibilities at what step tracks that can do notifications.
It can even read logs of how long it's set with somebody.
And so it builds in a lot of accountability into the process that we think we can get a lot more done.
Whose responsibilities are on how to put them all to the web to the website?
That does not exist.
That we don't put anything on the web.
We don't put any policies on the website right now and that's one of the reasons why we want to
begin this.
That's just a small piece.
Certainly.
So the responsibility is that the track all this stuff now.
I'm tracking a spreadsheet but that's kind of just falling off the rails just the whole process is
too clunky.
It just doesn't work.
Like you said, at the time it gets back around after everybody's reviewed it, legal review, that takes
quite a bit of time.
A lot of things have changed, even that policy has changed by then.
So where is it stored on the server?
Do you mean this currently?
Where is it stored?
Yeah, it's our software.
I don't mean he's doing that.
He's putting it in there to store it.
You're the only one, but it does all of them.
I don't create them.
After it's approved.
That's what it is.
Yes, I don't create it internally.
It's a piece of paper floating around.
The office, the office.
The reason we do that is it may be a street.
Issue that we're dealing with, but it has ramifications for the place to learn.
So the place to learn and use to work at it as well as streets and legal.
So this keeps this from happening and everybody just getting email sign off on it and then it goes
to the next person.
Yep, we log into the system, into library, log in, make changes, post them, and notify the next person.
You need to Jill's done, now it's your turn.
Jill had it for six days, now the clock's on you, you need to do your view.
sign off on it and it needs to go legal, legal has so much time and we do there in you.
And again, it will give us an external ability to publish so that people don't have to come ask for all these policies that we want to publish externally.
What's the time on on implementation?
As soon as you approve it and we get it signed and sent back to Dr. Track, we're going to schedule training.
There's going to be two of us that are going to be the administrators of this.
I'll be one of them.
I'll be the second one and we'll start training and kind of tell them what we need and then we'll bring in departments.
We'll probably get one department and let them be the getting big and then I'm hoping.
Well, I want to get this much sooner.
I would say a good well with Christmas.
I'm going to say a scout.
Is there a scout?
There's a scout will work on the on the doctorate.
It will medit in April and then in June and go live in August.
That looks like that looks like theirs.
That's their document.
That's a sample timeline.
Well, so you could go that in one, two, three, five months from time you started.
With budgeting starting with for me personally, I can see that.
Is this money budgeted somewhere?
Yes.
We've been working on this for a while.
She's been evaluating and reviewing everything that is out there.
We've got to go.
We've had several meetings as a group to go over the different pros and cons of the applications until we near it down to this this product.
IT was involved in that.
Yes.
The question they're concerned for.
I think it'd be good if at some point we can actually see some kind of return on investment like.
Sure.
What is the idea is that you'll be able to see these policies.
And but I'm saying let's let's kind of document the process currently and then going forward.
I think it'd be good for us to see that.
I mean provided that we pass it this evening.
Just to kind of get a feel for hey, this is what you guys did and here's what we were doing and here's what we're doing now.
And that's that would be my only request.
Exactly.
What I'm going to do when I bring ask you to revoke the current policy.
I'm going to revoke the current policy.
us to do a standard operating procedure.
So I'll compare that to what we're doing
and what we want to do with Dr.
or what Dr. Hulchins.
We're also, we're talking a lot about policies
that this will work with a lot of different forms
that we handle right now to memorize.
The number of forms that HR has to go from the part
to the part of the department to get signed off.
And trying to do it right to hire a person
and trying to do a payroll change.
Those have to be signed off or by five or six kinds of people
in different areas and sometimes different buildings
that that will be something that's going to look like
probably going to be also through the software.
So it's not just a policy and S&P software.
It's also going to help us with other dealings.
So what I'm getting out of this discussion is this, we'll make
your jobs easier.
I'm going to make a motion to approve.
Thank you.
We're going to slide number 10 up to this next spot and look for a motion on
the purchase of the AI Enterprise subscription.
Post will provide consumer data for the trust.
This will discuss the last meeting, but it needs to be on MSU agent
because the funds are coming out of the account for flooding.
It could not have said that better.
This was exactly correct. Yeah, thank you emotionally approve.
Excuse me.
Hi.
Williams.
Silver.
Perfect.
Five.
Six.
Colleagues.
Most two proof.
Five.
Hi.
Williams.
Silver.
Hi.
Part.
Five.
Seven.
Need a motion on the minutes for the November 6th.
2023.
Most two proof.
Five.
Williams.
Silver.
Perfect.
Five.
Eight.
Good.
El Stratton Edmunds.
And Paul R. Klein.
For GRDA.
Realizing amount of $720.
So may your members the council.
These are for professional services and assessments.
Encouraged from September 22nd through October 18th.
On behalf of the city.
Primarily, folks on review and pleadings,
filings and other documentation,
they're in response.
They're too communicating with the MIMA team.
Related to dam safety issues,
releasing and studying plan,
contaminate and sediment study,
transport, and the in-off amendment,
and the circuit court of appeals follow-up.
In this capacity,
good El Stratton is serving as a consultant to DWT,
where I would say the bulk of this work is being done.
But all the same items are being discussed.
So this is $720.
Coming from our budget.
If this claim is approved,
that would leave us $636,000.
$770.95 in that fiscal year,
$224.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Hi.
Williams.
Sandwich.
Hi.
I'm Mike McCoy-Man from BIMSCOL.
The GRDA relaxing thing and associated complaint
for citizens in the amount of $32,391 in 20 cents.
So clearly DWT is a much larger team with much larger resources
that are working on our behalf.
This invoice is for work performed from October 1st through October 31st
the entire month of October. Related to the same issues and topics that I had read off earlier,
but again, this is a much larger team working on this. Again, with our budget that we have set aside
with this 32,000 if it were approved tonight, that would leave us a balance of...
$640,380 and 75 cents for the fiscal year, 2324 for the usage of items.
Journey update, and we can share.
No, probably nothing, you know, that strategic, really, a lot of set of weight.
This has been a lot of discussion regarding, you know, the safety issues, and the licensing
study plan, but we anticipate a lot of this work is building up to what we're going to
be here, probably in February, so that'll probably be a far more active month and
fact, very smith, very smith, good health stradden, very boring, very boring, thank you.
That we work with all the time, but I think I'd like to have him come up and have some discussion
with the council probably around the first year.
There are some strategic things that we need to be talking about, and probably in an executive
session, but January would be a more appropriate time, so you might think about that,
but I think there's some stuff we're going to want to cover in the re-licensing, we're at this
stage, we're having to respond, this is the thing that's good.
Thank you.
Hi.
So cool.
So good.
Hi.
I've purchased the agreement to bake bank, I'll grant like, for Q23-62 for a caterpillar
mini excavator for electric department.
It'd be a related signing and payment authority to the City Manager or his dozen main.
I'm Councillor.
We sum up, annotations for those who've been up to 27 different when we get institutions, and we
had good responses time.
We had six group that.
the prices that came in range high of 8.50 97 right these are I mean this
many excavator and the bucket truck are these what we were trying to buy in the
pasture and Tyler made and why this is kind of rolled into this year like a
lot of things right a lot of things
Just a day we thought we were going to talk.
It just hit me.
I don't kind of thought we were going to do.
You guys have any questions about it?
Make a motion.
I approve.
Thank you.
Williams.
Michael.
Hi.
12 award-least person.
To bank the grant link for key 23-63 for a bucket truck for the electric department.
You've related signing and payment authority to a city manager or his does it need.
On this one,
I'm the second.
I'm the third.
Thank you.
Second.
Hi.
Thank you.
13.
Another new business of any, which is a residence of the Postman of the
14 staff reports.
15, community trustee community announcements.
16.
In the ground.
Second.
All right.
Five.
All right, goodbye.